JONATHAN NASCIMENTO WELZEL

Frontend Software Developer based in Oranienburg contact@jonwelzel.online | +49 0176 69494588 linkedin.com/in/jonwelzel | jonwelzel.online | github.com/jnwelzel

PROFILE

Advanced frontend developer with a keen eye for detail and over 10 years of experience in structuring, developing and maintaining applications. With solid experience in both back-end and frontend development for the web and desktop.

SKILLS OVERVIEW

- 5+ years of Java full stack development
- 7+ years of frontend development
- React proficiency and frontend ecosystem
- Mentoring
- Node and Ruby experience
- Databases Oracle DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB
- Cloud infrastructure management (AWS)
- Agile methodologies (Scrum and Kanban), TDD, Git, CI and CD

EXPERIENCE

Experienced Software Engineer

MediaMarktSaturn Technology (08-2021 to present)

- Our small team revamped the loyalty program for both brands of the company in different countries.
- Created landing pages as part of the new B2B customer registration process.
- Updated Contentful types and data and synced them with our REST API backend using GraphQL.
- Created translation jobs for different languages using Phrase.
- Spearheaded the implementation of the company's new design system within our team
- Performed multiple active monitoring sessions prior/after important sales campaigns and rollouts in new countries.

Senior Frontend Engineer

Wunderflats GmbH (03-2019 to 07-2021)

- Reduced bounce rate and increased adoption for mobile users of our platform by introducing SEO improvements and reshaping critical parts of the application.
- Worked closely with the design team to introduce more consistent patterns in the frontend and improve reusability for all frontend developers.

- Mentoring of junior frontend developers.
- Worked on our Node backend implementing new features and fixing performance issues.

Senior Full Stack Developer

Resultados Digitais (11-2017 to 02-2019)

- Helped my experimental growth team to successfully improve the product's user adoption.
- Actively participated and contributed to our frontend guild by helping to establish some good practices, patterns and other topics in order to improve frontend development.
- Improved code quality by refactoring legacy JavaScript + JQuery application to ReactJs components.

Front-end Developer

Mercos (09-2015 to 11-2017)

- Improved our product's stability by scaling and fine-tuning our AWS infrastructure.
- Implemented an easy way for our customers to check our product's status by creating a status page, which automatically kicked in as soon as things went south.
- Increased operational control of our product by creating New Relic metrics, and improving our Codeship CI flow.
- Made a switch to frontend development so I could start an open-source project for the company's React components and also helped introduce React and other tools into our frontend stack in order to offer a better experience for users and developers alike.
- Actively participated as one of the lead frontend devs in designing and building a B2B application from scratch.

Full Stack Developer

TOTVS (12-2013 to 09-2015)

- Decreased QA allocation times by automating our application's UI tests using Selenium.
- Increased our platform's widgets count. One I particularly liked adding was a layout editor where users could completely change the look of their corporate portal.
- Switched to a frontend developer position in order to be involved in working on a new product with a team from Silicon Valley (TOTVS Labs), where I was directly responsible for pushing our product's UI forward using Angular and Grails.

Full Stack Developer

Cipher (10-2012 to 11-2013)

- Enabled our product to securely connect to remote devices through SSH by using a Java framework called JSch in order to assess possible vulnerability issues.
- Fixed bugs and implemented a plethora of features in our web application product which used Vaadin.
- Was responsible for expanding our product's vulnerability analysis by designing and creating an Android client for our solution, which was responsible for checking a

device for any known vulnerabilities and reporting back to our web application through a REST API.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (2006-2010)

Federal Technological University of Paraná (UTFPR) - Medianeira, PR - Brazil

Coursework in Software Analysis and Development